# **Matias Bettera Marcat**

# **Physicist**

Last update: January 17, 2024

Up-to-date version of CV is available at

https://mbetteram.github.io/online-resume

Residence	♠ Cordoba
LinkedIn	in Matias Bettera Marcat
GitHub	mbetteram
Mobile	+54 9 358 483 4287
Email	bettera.marcat@gmail.com

Physicist, currently finishing a PhD. Researching in biophysics, and interested in science and technology. With a strong background in mathematics and physics, and experience facing problems with modeling, simulations a statistic analysis. Linux, Open and Free software enthusiast.

Skills: Fortran, C, Bash/Shell scripting, ssh, gnuplot, Python, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn, jupyter, Git/Github, scikit-learn, tensorflow, SQL

# **Professional Experience**

Mar 2023 - Present

#### **Proffessor**

<u>Universidad Empresarial Siglo 21</u> is a bussiness oriented private university. I am proffessor of theoretical and poblem clases of many mathematics courses, statcis and physics.

```
    __Distance courses__ _(two months period)_: Physics, Statics, Mathematical Analisys, Algebra.
    __Presential intensive courses__ _(two months period)_: Mathematical Analisys, Statistics II.
    __Presential courses__ _(four months period)_: Mathematical Analisys.
```

May 2023 - Sep 2023

### Monitoring teacher

My role at <u>Data science diploma</u>, <u>at FAMAF-UNC</u> consisted in the monitoring, advising and evaluation of assignments, of four groups of four people each.

```
Python (jupyter) (numpy) (pandas) (matplotlib) (seaborn) (SQL) (scikit-learn) (tensorflow) (Git)
```

Mar 2022 - Present, Mar 2016 - Jul 2016

### Lecturer (Profesor Ayudante de Primera.)

Lecturer for problem classes. Evaluation of midterm and final examns.

```
    __2nd term 23__ Thermodynamics and Statistical Mechanics II _and_ Modern Physics I
    __1st term 23__ Thermodynamics and Statistical Mechanics I _and_ Physics 4 (Modern Physics)
    __2nd term 22__ General Physics III (Electricity and Magnetism).
    __1st term 22__ Thermodynamics and Statistical Mechanics I.
    __1st term 16__ General Physics IV (Waves and Optics).
```

March 2022 - Feb 2023

## Lecturer (Profesor Ayudante B D.S.)

Lecturer for problem classes. Evaluation of midterm and final examns.

```
_ Feb 22__ Admission and introductory course._ 2nd term 22__ Mechanics_ 1st term 22__ Admission and introductory course.
```

#### Research

Research fellowship, granted by CONICET. (Beca Interna Doctoral de CONICET)

Research on active matter, particularly sperm dynamics in confined environments, with simulations and experimental data analysis.

(Investigación sobre materia activa, en particular dinámica de espermátozoides en ambientes confinados, con simulaciones y análisis de datos experimentales.)



Aug 2014 - Jul 2015, Aug 2012 - Jul 2013

## Student assistant (Alumno Ayudante de Segunda D.S.)

Student assistant for problem classes. - 1st term 15 Electromagnetism I - 2nd term 14 General Physics I (Introduction to Mechanics) - 1st term 13 Mechanics - 2nd term 12 Electromagnetism I

### Education

**Diploma** in Data Science and its applications (FaMAF, UNC) [2020]

PhD in Physics, research on Dynamics of microconfined swimmers. Mathematichs, Astronomy, Physics and Computer Science school, UNC, AR. (*Doctorado en Físca*. FaMAF, UNC. Investigación: Dinámica de nadadores microconfinados, FaMAF, UNC) [2016 - Present]
PhD Courses: Numerical Methods in Astrophysics, Computational Physics, Fluid Mechanics, Topics in Mathematical Biology, Introduction to LAMMPS code.

**B.S. in Physics**, Final grad work: Simultaneous uptake model of water and nutrients by crop roots. Physics department, UNRC, AR. (*Licenciatura en Física*, *Trabajo Final: Modelo de toma simultánea de agua y nutrientes por raíces de cultivos. UNRC*) [2010 - 2016]